Do you consider yourself wealthy?
你觉得自己富有吗？
Do you have enough cash in the bank to have no financial worries?
你是否有足够的现金，没有经济上的担忧？
Or maybe, like me, being rich is just something you can only dream about?
或者，也许像我一样，富有仅仅是你只能梦想的事情？
For most of us, the most likely way to become a millionaire is to win the lottery, but without buying a ticket, what other ways are there to get super- rich?
对大多数人来说，最可能成为百万富翁的机会是中彩票，但如果不买彩票，还有其他办法成为超级富豪吗？
A ‘super-rich‘ person is often defined as someone with over $30 million dollars of assets - so it’s not just about having a suitcase stuffed full of banknotes!
“超级富豪”通常指资产超过3000万美元的人——所以这不仅仅是拥有一只装满钞票的行李箱那么简单！
They usually own property, an expensive yacht or eat in swanky restaurants.
他们通常拥有房产、昂贵的游艇，或者在豪华餐厅用餐。
And there appear to be more and more of these people, as it‘s reported that the number of super- rich is expected to increase by 43% over the next decade.
而且这类人似乎越来越多，有报道称，未来十年超级富豪的数量预计将增加43%。
If you save your pennies, make the right investments and work hard, could you be one of them?
如果你省吃俭用、正确地投资并努力工作，能成为他们中的一员吗？
It’s unlikely because a report last year highlighted inequality in the world, saying the richest 62 individuals owned as much as the poorest 50%.
可能性不大，因为去年一份报告强调了全球的不平等现象，称最富有的62个人拥有的财富相当于最贫穷的50%人口的总和。
But for those lucky ones who are loaded, what is it that they splash the cash on?
但对于那些幸运的富豪来说，他们会把钱花在什么上面呢？
One academic in the UK, Emma Spence, has been researching just that - and her answer is yachts!
英国学者艾玛·斯彭斯一直在研究这个问题——她的答案是游艇！
It‘s the ultimate status symbol but she also says “a superyacht is essentially a black hole of wealth” - in other words, it continually eats your money and doesn’t increase in value like an art collection might.
游艇是终极身份象征，但她也表示“超级游艇本质上是财富黑洞”，换句话说，它会持续消耗你的钱，而且不会像艺术品收藏那样升值。
But if you‘ve got the spare cash, why not have one!
但如果你有闲钱，为什么不买一艘呢？
It’s an excuse to show off your wealth and position in society.
这是一个炫耀财富和社会地位的理由。
Interestingly, Emma Spence found that the size of someone‘s yacht shows their place in the pecking order.
有趣的是，艾玛·斯彭斯发现，游艇的大小能体现一个人在等级体系中的地位。
This is a good example of conspicuous consumption - buying something so someone else notices.
这是“炫耀性消费”的典型例子——购买某样东西就是为了让别人注意到。
In the past you may have expected to find a super- rich, yacht- owning, billionaire to live in developed countries like the USA but now the wealthy can be found hanging out in most corners of the world.
过去，你可能会认为拥有游艇、超级富有的亿万富翁会住在像美国这样的发达国家，但现在在世界大多数角落都能看到富豪的身影。
According to a report by Knight Frank, Vietnam is the country expected to have the fastest growth of super- rich over the next 10 years - an amazing 170% increase.
根据莱坊房地产咨询公司的一份报告，越南是未来10年超级富豪数量增长最快的国家——增幅惊人，达170%。
If all this makes you feel poor, remember that being wealthy doesn‘t necessarily make you happy.
如果这些让你觉得自己贫穷，记住，富有不一定能让你快乐。
You don’t have to waste time worrying about what to spend your money on.
你不必花时间纠结该把钱花在哪里。
And you can feel rich in other ways by having good friends and family, good health or just a happy life - things that don‘t cost the earth.
而且你还可以通过拥有亲密的朋友和家人、健康的身体，或者仅仅是幸福的生活来感受“富有”——这些都无需花费巨额财富。
And if you really want a yacht, how about a toy one to play with in the bath?!
如果你真的想要一艘游艇，买个能在浴缸里玩的玩具游艇怎么样？
How rich do you feel today?
今天的你觉得自己有多“富有”呢？